<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>regulations archivos - Tapinpack by tictap</title>
	<atom:link href="/en/category/regulations/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/en/category/regulations/</link>
	<description>Etiquetaje digital</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 12:06:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/cropped-faviconfaviconTP-32x32.png</url>
	<title>regulations archivos - Tapinpack by tictap</title>
	<link>/en/category/regulations/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>What information should alcoholic drink labels provide within the EU?</title>
		<link>/en/what-information-should-alcoholic-drinks-lavels-provide-within-the-eu/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[olinta]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 11:22:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[regulations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sin categorizar]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/what-information-should-alcoholic-drinks-lavels-provide-within-the-eu/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The European Union has very strict regulations regarding the information that alcoholic beverages must show to protect the health of consumers and ensure greater transparency in the market. Here we describe the information required by European Union legislation on alcoholic beverages. Nutritional Information Since 13 December 2016, all alcoholic beverages sold in the European Union &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/en/what-information-should-alcoholic-drinks-lavels-provide-within-the-eu/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">What information should alcoholic drink labels provide within the EU?</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>La entrada <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/what-information-should-alcoholic-drinks-lavels-provide-within-the-eu/">What information should alcoholic drink labels provide within the EU?</a> se public贸 primero en <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/">Tapinpack by tictap</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-ast-global-color-8-color has-text-color">The European Union has very strict regulations regarding the information that alcoholic beverages must show to protect the health of consumers and ensure greater transparency in the market. Here we describe the information required by European Union legislation on alcoholic beverages.</p>



<p class="has-ast-global-color-8-color has-text-color"><strong>Nutritional Information</strong></p>



<p class="has-ast-global-color-8-color has-text-color">Since 13 December 2016, all alcoholic beverages sold in the European Union must display detailed nutritional information on their labels. This includes the amount of energy, fats, saturated fats, carbohydrates, sugars, proteins, and salt in the drink. Additional information about vitamins and minerals may also be included.</p>



<p class="has-ast-global-color-8-color has-text-color">This measure aims to help consumers make more informed decisions about their diet and avoid excessive consumption of alcoholic beverages.</p>



<p class="has-ast-global-color-8-color has-text-color"><strong>Health warnings</strong></p>



<p class="has-ast-global-color-8-color has-text-color">Since 13 December 2014, all alcoholic beverages sold in the European Union <strong>must display health warnings on their labels</strong> which <strong>a</strong>im to raise consumers&#8217; awareness of the risks of alcohol abuse and promote responsible consumption.</p>



<p class="has-ast-global-color-8-color has-text-color">These warnings should include the <strong>amount of alcohol in the drink</strong>, along with messages that warn of the dangers of excessive alcohol consumption, such as: &#8220;Alcohol abuse is harmful to health&#8221;.</p>



<p class="has-ast-global-color-8-color has-text-color"><strong>Allergies and intolerances</strong></p>



<p class="has-ast-global-color-8-color has-text-color">Since 13 December 2014, all alcoholic beverages sold in the European Union must display <strong>information on allergies and intolerances on their labels</strong>. This includes information on the presence of allergens such as gluten, peanuts, milk, and eggs, and aims to help people with allergies and food intolerances identify ingredients that could cause an allergic reaction.</p>



<p class="has-ast-global-color-8-color has-text-color"><strong>Origin and content</strong></p>



<p class="has-ast-global-color-8-color has-text-color">From 1 January 2019, all alcoholic beverages sold in the European Union must display <strong>information about their origin and content on their labels</strong>, with the aim of ensuring transparency in the market and protecting consumers against food fraud<strong>.</strong></p>



<p class="has-ast-global-color-8-color has-text-color">. This includes information on the region of production, the country of origin and the variety of grapes used in the case of wines.</p>



<p class="has-ast-global-color-8-color has-text-color">In conclusion, the European Union has very strict regulations regarding the information that alcoholic beverages must show on their labels. This information includes nutritional information, health warnings, information on allergies and intolerances, origin, and content. These measures aim to protect consumer health, promote responsible consumption and ensure market transparency.</p>
<p>La entrada <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/what-information-should-alcoholic-drinks-lavels-provide-within-the-eu/">What information should alcoholic drink labels provide within the EU?</a> se public贸 primero en <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/">Tapinpack by tictap</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What should you know about the new labeling of alcoholic beverages?</title>
		<link>/en/what-should-you-know-about-the-new-labeling-of-alcoholic-beverages/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[olinta]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 12:50:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[regulations]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/what-should-you-know-about-the-new-labeling-of-alcoholic-beverages/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>If you are a producer or consumer of alcoholic beverages, you should be aware of the new European regulation 2023 that regulates the labeling of these products. The aim of this regulation is to improve consumer information and to prevent misleading or confusing practices by manufacturers. What information should be included on the label of &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/en/what-should-you-know-about-the-new-labeling-of-alcoholic-beverages/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">What should you know about the new labeling of alcoholic beverages?</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>La entrada <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/what-should-you-know-about-the-new-labeling-of-alcoholic-beverages/">What should you know about the new labeling of alcoholic beverages?</a> se public贸 primero en <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/">Tapinpack by tictap</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div class="wp-block-media-text alignwide is-stacked-on-mobile" style="margin-bottom:var(--wp--preset--spacing--40);grid-template-columns:44% auto"><figure class="wp-block-media-text__media"><img decoding="async" width="561" height="285" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/WINE-BOOLE.png" alt="" class="wp-image-500 size-full" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/WINE-BOOLE.png 561w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/03/WINE-BOOLE-300x152.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 561px) 100vw, 561px" /></figure><div class="wp-block-media-text__content">
<p class="has-ast-global-color-7-color has-text-color">If you are a producer or consumer of alcoholic beverages, you should be aware of the new European regulation 2023 that regulates the labeling of these products. The aim of this regulation is to improve consumer information and to prevent misleading or confusing practices by manufacturers.</p>
</div></div>



<h4 class="has-ast-global-color-1-color has-text-color">What information should be included on the label of an alcoholic beverage?</h4>



<p class="has-ast-global-color-7-color has-text-color">Under the new rules, all alcoholic beverages with a volume of alcohol greater than 1.2% must include on the label the following data: </p>



<p class="has-ast-global-color-7-color has-text-color">&#8211; <strong>Name or denomination</strong>(origin) of the drink: must indicate the type of drink it is (wine, beer, liquor, etc.). </p>



<p class="has-ast-global-color-7-color has-text-color">&#8211; Name of the <strong>manufacturer</strong>: You must clearly identify who made the drink and where your headquarters or establishment are. </p>



<p class="has-ast-global-color-7-color has-text-color">&#8211; <strong>If it contains allergens</strong> or if it can cause adverse reactions: you should warn the consumer if the drink contains any ingredient that can cause an allergic reaction or intolerance (such as sulfites, gluten, lactose, etc.). </p>



<p class="has-ast-global-color-7-color has-text-color">&#8211; A symbol indicating the low <strong>alcohol content (between 2% and 6%) or high (more than 6%)</strong>: it must inform the consumer about the alcohol content of the drink and its possible health effects.</p>



<h4 class="has-ast-global-color-1-color has-text-color">What benefits does this regulation have for consumers?</h4>



<p class="has-ast-global-color-7-color has-text-color">This regulation has several benefits for consumers:</p>



<p class="has-ast-global-color-7-color has-text-color">On the one hand, it raises the level of protection and reduces errors in the perception of the drink due to incorrect labeling: it prevents the consumer from becoming confused about the type, origin, or quality of the drink he buys or consumes.</p>



<p class="has-ast-global-color-7-color has-text-color">It also seeks <strong>to prevent misleading practices by alcohol companies</strong>: it prevents companies from using false or misleading names, images, or claims to attract or mislead consumers.</p>



<p class="has-ast-global-color-7-color has-text-color">It also calls for <strong>greater market transparency and fair competition</strong>: it ensures that all producers and distributors comply with the same rules and conditions and respect consumers&#8217; rights and interests.</p>



<p class="has-ast-global-color-7-color has-text-color">The idea is that<strong> it allows for more informed and health-conscious decisions:</strong>by including nutritional information and allergens, consumers can better understand the energy value, nutrients and substances that can affect their health (such as sugars, saturated fats, or salt) that each drink contains.</p>



<p class="has-ast-global-color-7-color has-text-color">If you want to know more about the solution that Tapinpack offers for compliance with this regulation, do not hesitate to contact us.</p>
<p>La entrada <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/what-should-you-know-about-the-new-labeling-of-alcoholic-beverages/">What should you know about the new labeling of alcoholic beverages?</a> se public贸 primero en <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/">Tapinpack by tictap</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
